WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
Right. It is the Survivor
SA: Philippines reunion show
live from Cape Town
with Tom Swartz
just won a million rand
as well as a Huawei prize
package, which includes...
Which includes the Huawei
P20 Pro and MateBook X bundle,
a watch, a 360 degree camera -
to name but a few wonderful prizes.
Tom, we've covered so much
already, but the night is far from over.
We have the entire cast
here from this amazing season.
Yeah. Round of applause.
Why not?
Tom. Congratulations.
Thank you very much.
To win this game, you
have to have so many factors
counting in your favour,
like you mentioned, Jeanne.
But what it ultimately comes
down to is just how you ebb and flow
with the game, how you adapt
with the things that
we throw at you.
You did that very well.
I tend to ebb, but I sort
of go against the flow.
Which you did very well.
Now, here's the thing.
What was your best
move of the game?
I think providing and
never, ever giving up.
Lots of nods from everyone else.
You can't get to where you are
without making some mistakes,
biggest mistake?
Opening my mouth.
I just needed to change feet,
but also to have just
enough time to lick a spoon.
I was just going to say, you
talked about eating as well, right?
Jeanne, incredible achievement.
Making it this far in the
game. Second place.
Looking back in
retrospect, is there anything
you would have done differently?
I think I would have
liked to come in the game
and been a big character
like Tevin or Wern or Tom
and dominated in that way.
But I saw quite early on that
I couldn't be that character,
and that kind of
made me a bit sad
cos that's the kind of
character I like to watch on TV.
But I think my biggest regret is
voting Wern out after seeing that.
So...
Oh, well. His vote wouldn't
have counted anyway. So...
Every single move
in this game counts.
And it's true of
that one as well.
OK. So, no matter how great
a player you are in this game
or how better a
player you might be,
one thing you can't get
by without is relationships.
It's a currency in this game
and we had all kinds
of those this season.
I'm going to start with
with Tom and Chane.
Chane, you two
had, like, some...
It was like a best friend thing
going on right from the start.
We thought it was going
all the way to the end.
It went south very quickly.
Was it just Tom's table manners?
It played a very big part.
No, I'm joking!
But when we went
to Visayas tribe
and Tom lost his
temper quite a bit
and for my gameplay, I
just thought that it'll be better
if I step back and side
with Palesa and Vusi.
OK. Good answer. Tom,
I must just add that if I have to
go with Chane and back her up
in the fact that I will never look
at a chocolate fountain again
in the same way.
Thank you!
Palesa, with Tom again.
Interesting relationship.
You had almost the flip of that
because you were arch enemies
from the get-go and
that beautiful moment
where you won that
challenge together
and he creeped into your heart.
Old-school charm, right?
- I don't know about heart, but...
- Mine or yours?
But I mean, Tom and I
were big personalities
and we were too
bold in the crawl.
So of course we were meant
to clash in some sort of way.
But those personalities
are two people
that are also when they
work together, you know,
bring out something epic.
Indeed, it was epic to
watch you guys going at it.
Let's talk about you, because
you also had some sort
of strange and wonderful
conglomeration of
relationships going on there.
I'm going to... You know what?
I'm going to ask Katinka this.
But first, big it up for the
youngest player of the season.
Here's a question.
Katinka... The don. Be honest.
Did he have his girls
wrapped around his finger?
I didn't feel like I was
wrapped around his finger.
I think... Well, Werner
played a really good game,
but I really think that we
formed a really good relationship
which is going to
continue out of the game.
- Like I said, wrapped around the finger.
- Yeah. - Yeah.
Annalize...
Your answer to that question?
Well, I had to play the
game just to be with the don,
but I was definitely not
wrapped around his finger.
At some stage, he was wrapped
around mine and no-one even knew that.
- I knew that, Anna.
- Thank you. Thank you.
OK. Betrayal. Huge
part of this game.
We know it's part of the game.
You expect it to
come at some point,
but when it does,
sometimes it cuts really deep.
- Toni, you experienced it that way.
- Yep. Tissues.
I'm joking. Betrayal for me
was with Werner, definitely.
We connected so well, but
like this was war in a way.
And in any war and
anything that's, like, traumatic,
there's collateral damage,
but there's collateral beauty,
which was the friendships.
This is collateral beauty.
So I've got a collateral
beauty out of all of this,
as well as matching tattoos
with my two guys here.
So, I mean, the betrayal
came with some some beauty.
And where is it at now?
Have you guys made
up? Everything fine again?
No, I'm never talking
to him again. I'm joking!
You look so worried.
Werner and I are going to enter
My Kitchen Rules next, maybe, hey?
Hunt on live TV.
OK. So much to talk
about, so little time,
but we are not done just yet.
After the break, we'll be
talking idols and blindsides.
And we also find out
who you, the viewer,
voted as the Mahindra fan
favourite player of the season.
Plus, a huge announcement.
Stay right where you are.
As I flipped over the shell,
there was an envelope.
"Congratulations.
"You've found a clue to
a hidden immunity idol."
If I have to
eat it, I'll eat it.
I'm not going back to
the camp with that clue.
That clue does not exist.
So that's automatically five.
We've got a majority.
..the blindside. He's a threat.
He's got to go. First one out.
If we pull this off,
it'll be amazing.
Well, I love your work, girl.
Oh, thank you!
Seamus.
Let's pull a blindside.
This is damn awesome.
- Why don't we do that?
- I give you my word.
- That's my word.
- What did they do?
I could make him think
that we have an idea.
His eyes beam up.
And then I know that
I think I've got him.
Reveal.
Neil, you have the white rock.
That means you are voted out.
My idol is gone!
Would you put that
in your pants, please?
Because that belongs to me.
Oh, goodness' sake!
Ace and I, we think we found a
clue to the hidden immunity idol.
- I'm so excited!
- Does anybody have any idea what I said?
I'm not going home today.
I found the idol.
I don't believe you.
Ace, the tribe has spoken.
One idol, everybody knows about,
and that's why he has
a target on his back.
The second one is the
one that we can play with.
Do you want me to keep that one?
I will use this idol
to protect our lives.
The best part of a blindside
is not letting him see it come.
Tevin, the tribe has spoken.
I get a clue.
I'm never going to tell
anybody about the idol.
There's no idols showing up.
No.
PK, I think that is indeed
a hidden immunity idol.
I'm playing for myself.
Three immunity idols playing.
I found a package.
I love this game.
If anyone has a hidden immunity
idol and you'd like to play it,
now would be the time to do so.
Palesa, you need
to bring me a torch.
If Werner doesn't win
immunity, let's get him out.
Tom, you don't stand a
chance against Werner.
You see, she's got a
plan to upset everybody.
When we get to
four, we vote you off.
True story. I know that
you're a fan, Jeanne.
I would like you to
come to the front,
and I want to give
you an opportunity
to play an idol for yourself.
Katinka.
The tribe has spoken.
You are watching Survivor
SA: Philippines reunion show live
from the Mother City, Cape Town.
There is so much to catch up on.
It is time for us to
do some idle talk.
I'm going to start with you.
I'm going to... Let's
just say what it was.
You were the idol
bloodhound of the season.
Did you come into the show
thinking you're going
to find every idol you can
and just search all the time?
Not really.
Because the thing is, it's very
hard trying to control these people
and then there's idols as well.
So the best thing to do
with them is to find them
and put them in your own bag
and then the game can go on.
- It's as simple as that.
- So it was a strategy
cos you kept searching even
when all the idols were gone.
- I never stopped.
- Every morning!
Ace, how frustrating!
How frustrating because
you spent an entire day
just digging up the whole camp
with a little bit of
help from a friend.
And then he comes
in, in one fell swoop,
he just finds it
almost effortlessly.
I just got back
from the Philippines,
now straight to Cape Town.
Right from the start,
I was thrown curveballs
and then eventually the
game threw a curveball.
I dug a grave and
they buried me in it.
Well, at least, you
know, you dig very well.
It was beautiful to watch.
Palesa, something else
that was beautiful to watch
was you digging the
idol out at Tribal Council
and the looks on
everyone's faces.
What a surprise.
But, then, also, when you left
Tribal Council with
an idol in your pocket,
what did you need to
trigger you to play your idol?
What should have happened?
I think it wasn't anything,
any external that could
have convinced me
to play or not to play.
I had a fight in my own mind
from the moment I walked in.
Play, don't play.
And the last one that
came out was play.
But now I have a souvenir
for my 11-year-old
son, Loazi, to take home.
- Still wearing and proudly!
- Still am, always.
OK, let's talk about
another big moment.
PK, this one from you, the
night of the idol extravaganza.
I mean, you started all
of that, played an idol,
and then everyone was just
pulling idols out from everywhere.
Did you come in thinking
you're going to cause that chaos?
I mean, you know me,
I just needed security.
And once I found it in
that idol, I went to the pots.
I had to do what I
do, stirred the pots.
Got everybody thinking,
got everybody playing.
And, I mean, I wanted
to play a beautiful game
and I got a chance to do that.
And that idol gave me
an opportunity to do that.
Definitely a beautiful moment
in the game of Survivor.
One of the other elements of
this game that we love to watch
almost the most, I
think, are the blindsides,
usually orchestrated
by the castaways
using idols and strategies.
But sometimes, it's the
game that throws the blindside.
Neil, I'm talking about you.
Do you still shudder when
you see little white rocks?
I see white rocks
everywhere that I go now.
What does it feel like
leaving the game like that?
Well, look, there was a
bit of irony in it, leaving it,
but I left like a rock
star. It made for great TV.
But I do have something
that belongs to you.
I want to... I would
like to return to you.
I don't know why you're
still holding on to that.
That is bad luck! Throw it away!
Vusi, there you are.
Did that send the game
into a new direction for you?
Absolutely. I think it actually
showed that the game
is all about chance and luck.
And sometimes no matter how
much you play and how good you are,
if the wheels of
fortune are not with you,
you can just go straight out.
That is true indeed, especially
for someone like Seamus.
Seamus, you came into this
game, you played fast and hard.
You also left fast and hard!
But I do want to give it to you.
You brought it, so
thank you for doing that.
When you left, you said, you know,
this is going to be a boring season.
These guys just aren't
playing. What do you think now?
I've changed my mind completely.
They really did
escalate the game play,
as the game progressed and
as the first person voted out,
you know, there's not much I can
say to carry any form of validity here,
but they had a fantastic season
and congratulations to Tom.
You've definitely
earned it, well done.
Well, these guys have just been
39 days in the game of Survivor,
so they know how tough it is.
But no matter how much we try
and prepare our new castaways to let
them know how
rough it's going to be,
it just, it's almost
always a rude awakening.
Here's a little reminder.
Assuming you don't have
rice, you never got that, right?
Yeah, that's our only problem.
- You guys have nothing for food.
- Nothing. - Literally nothing.
Just coconuts.
Oh, my word.
We pretty much ran out of food.
We don't have food any more.
Going to get hungry.
Maybe we should then
go fish, while it's like this.
- Can you fish?
- No.
Our wood is wet.
Everything is wet.
We actually feeling the fatigue
coming in, myself and Toni.
I've had a runny tummy.
I'm on day four without
having an actual meal.
So we're in the
worst place right now.
It sucks.
I'm like, we need to maybe
look for a fish, but there's no way
I can go into that water.
I can't even go into the
water to wash myself.
I'm so tired and depleted.
Someone please give
Toni a hug. Come on.
They must all
give me a hug later!
Loads of hugs waiting to happen.
Toni, how tough was this?
It was brutal.
That moment especially
was very brutal.
But even the day that that episode
was on, driving home that day,
I just started crying because
I remember that very dark
place that we woke up in.
But people are waking up like
that every day in the real world.
So, you know, it really just makes
you reflect and it really humbles
you into, like, it's like realise
what your blessings are.
Once again,
life-changing this game is.
PK. Yeah, yeah, well done.
PK, you came into this
game built like a machine.
You left like a small machine.
How tough was it for you?
It was probably the toughest
thing I've ever done, you know?
I mean, one thing I did realise,
though, is that as human beings,
you think you need to eat food or do
something like maybe eat a banana
before you go to the gym.
But then I realised that we
have so much energy inside of us.
You don't need to get
energy anywhere else
except from inside of you.
And that's one thing
Survivor taught me. It's in here.
One of the questions I get asked
most about this game and I think
it's true for you guys as well
now, is whether or not this game
is as rough as it
looks on screen.
You know, does it look,
is it as bad as it looks?
And I always tell
people, no, it's not.
It's much, much worse.
There's no way we can
convey to the viewers
what you guys go through.
But there is something we can
show you to give you an inkling
of how bad it gets, and that
is how much weight they lose.
And together...
- Jeanne...
- You can't fake that.
You can't fake that.
No, you can't.
I put all that weight back on, so...
We lost the weight, but I
found it again, so that's fine.
Oh, no, it's brutal.
It's not just the food.
The food is one thing,
but your mind is racing
100 million miles a minute.
But it's also
starved of anything -
information, news, the things
that we consume every single day,
and that also the
boredom kills you.
And it's a whole
bunch of things.
It's being dirty, it's being
wet, your body is chafing.
Everything is awful.
Everything is awful,
except a few of the people.
But some of them were awful too!
Just joking.
Tom, you've got some
rice in your beard!
I will never eat rice or
coconut again in my life.
No lie!
As you know, Mahindra has
been running a fan favourite
competition
throughout the series.
And after the break, we'll find
out who of the entire cast received
the most votes.
We will also announce
which lucky viewer will win
a brand-new Mahindra.
And we chat to one of the most
talked about players of the season -
Marthunis.
This is the Survivor SA
Philippines live reunion show.
Do not go away.
Welcome to Survivor.
I can show them dumb blonde.
I will literally just be sitting on
the beach just looking like this.
I see Tom taking the
spoon and licking it.
I wanted to throw
up in my mouth.
Dude, two of those girls
had false eyelashes on.
- Really?
- Yes.
This is not Ibiza, darling. You're
not coming here to party scene.
You can blame me but
just remember, my name is...
Do I get to choose
somebody to go with me?
Are you preempting this?
Are you the host suddenly?
This thing has so much power to it that
every now and then I overstep my boundary,
now that I'm
wearing it. I'm sorry.
- New phone. - New phone, Darling.
- New phone.
Call me on my SHELLphone.
Tom is grating me.
He's going at it,
not even chewing.
Then he's in the fountain
with his whole hand, stuffing it.
Then he proceeds
to lick his whole hand.
Oh, I am not a quitter.
Honestly, I've come here to win.
I'm going to win this and
then also win Miss World
later this year as well.
The only thing I'll quit is
maybe a diet or a gym contract.
Welcome back.
This is the live reunion show
of Survivor SA Philippines,
live from Cape Town.
We'll be announcing the fan
favourite castaway in a moment.
But first, love him or hate him,
one of the most controversial
players of the season is Marthunis.
And you don't have to be a
member of Mensa to understand why.
Immediately, something that stands
out is a man wearing a suit and tie.
Now it's either he's come here
to play the game strategically
or he's just playing
the game very stupidly
because he's immediately
drawing attention to himself.
Good, guys, we've got water.
Who's this brother in his suit?
What is he doing?
Ladies, dinner in an hour.
Alpha males do
not run this place.
Tom, does your age give you
advantage or disadvantage?
Has your mouth ever
got you smacked?
If you die, life carries on.
I've got a wife and kids.
As if I don't have a life.
You are not leaving people
behind that rely on you.
Everything
Marthunis says is just,
he's like holding something
against you the entire time.
Do you...
Go get us some water.
Do the woman's job and
go get me some water.
Thanks. Go get us some
water. Do the woman's job.
Sexist, misogynistic ***.
Like, you guys think you're
going to blindside me, and...
Oh, it's so funny.
So what's your next
move going to be?
Quit just before
you guys can do that.
This game is too tough for you.
That's 100% correct.
Leave the torch.
What can I say, Marthunis?
We should have known when you were standing
on the boat at attention in a suit.
We should have known
what was coming, right?
Here's the thing. You left the
game under harsh circumstances.
I'm hoping that it wasn't
all negative for you.
Was there something
positive in it as well?
You know, Nico, I
came to Survivor to win.
I didn't come to make
friends, but I feel like a winner
because I made
these four friends.
These four guys next to me became
my friends, my Mindanao tribe.
And I feel like a winner.
You certainly are.
We had a fantastic cast this
season, including Marthunis.
And you had the
opportunity...
You had the opportunity
to vote for your favourite
in our Mahindra fan
favourite competition.
And just by voting, one of
the viewers is the lucky winner
of the Mahindra XUV500 W8.
Our winner is...
..Claudette Harmse.
Congratulations, Claudette.
All right.
So one of our viewers drives
away in a brand-new Mahindra.
But what about our castaways?
The winner of the fan
favourite vote also drives away
in a brand-new Mahindra.
Take a look at that.
The KUV100 NXT K8 petrol.
So one of our castaways,
one of the fan favourites,
will drive away in
that great Mahindra.
The three favourites
in the running are:
The biggest thing that's changed
inside of me is appreciation.
This has definitely taught
me a lot about myself.
I learned that I'm
stronger than I think I am.
It's been amazing.
I'm so blessed and so happy
to have been a part of this.
I got to play it.
Who will win the car?
Tom, would you
like to drive that?
Hell, yes.
Katinka, 19 years old.
That's a good place to start.
Being humble. I'm
going to start there.
That's a wonderful
place to have at any age.
Werner?
Wonderful prize.
It's time to find out which one of
them is our fan favourite winner.
And that person is none
other than the incredible...
..Werner!
You can go sit down.
Look at him, just ready to
jump in and drive away, right?
Congratulations, Werner.
Enjoy the Mahindra.
I got it right. I think...
Well, let me just ask the cast.
Were you guys surprised
that this guy was a pastor?
He played the
game like a pastor.
Except for the lying part!
The congregation.
Werner, fan favourite.
That means something...
You were doing
something right, OK?
Let's talk about your game.
Why do you want
to talk about me?
Was it life-changing for you?
Nico, for me, it felt like I
was on the outside looking in.
People know I applied
last time, didn't make it.
And I saw these guys
standing on the beach.
I felt, man, I'm happy for
you, but I wanted to be there.
So to be in the show,
it's just amazing.
Well, you have been amazing.
And I think everyone will agree,
it was wonderful
having you on the show.
We have one winner tonight,
the sole Survivor, Tom Swartz.
Tom, the winner of the show.
Yes.
What do you feel like right
now as you're sitting over there?
Slightly surreal.
It's starting to sink in now because
I'm starting to vibrate a bit more.
And the more we have
like these ad breaks,
the more these guys are
saying their drinks are on me.
So that's also making
it a bit more real.
We got to stop all of
that right there! OK.
Well, tell me this. Your life is
going to change from here on in.
How did it change the
moment you got off the island?
How did your perspective
on life change?
Getting home was, I think, just
one of the best days of my life.
Seeing the people that I love that
much, be that happy to see me back,
which included my wife!
And our house was a lot tidier
while I was away, apparently.